CURRICULUM VITAE



Dr. Apeksha Mendhe, AM ASCE (2017) BE, MTech, PhD (Civil Engineering), Mob: +91 8010996193/ +91 9511275003

Email: <u>alaskamendhe@gmail.com</u> aamendhe@gmail.com

Address: 27-A Fago Patil Layout, Behind

Dinshaws Factory Borgaon Gorewada Road, Gittikhadan,

Nagpur – 440013, Maharashtra, India

Social Networking: https://www.linkedin.com/in/apekshamendhe
Past Global Recognition: AM ASCE (USA) and GMICE (ICE LONDON)

BECIVIL ENGINEER/MTECHENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEER/DOCTORAL RESEARCH IN TRANSPORTATION ENGINEERING (PHD).

Civil engineer post graduated (M.tech) Environmental Engineering and completed Doctoral degree (Ph.D) in Transportation Engineering. <u>Present</u> (accomplished) Ph.D in Transportation Engineering, Road Safety Auditing work for Planning and design of motorized and Non-motorized traffic facilities. <u>Former</u> Project assistant (NEERI) Nagpur- 'Water Safety Plan in and Around Nagpur city'. Research scholar potential fit into Equivalent Professional position of Doctorate degree, Road Safety Audit development in Geometrical improvement pattern of transportation & traffic facilities.

RESEARCH COMPETENCY

Evidence based Sustainable practice for recognized behavior of non-motorized traffic o Planning and Practices for road users under safety audit after site operation examination

- o Guideline recommendation practices under traffic safety Auditing
- o DO Vs BOD relation using MCDM- fuzzy technique
- o Memberships of IWA, ASCE, ORCID id, Researcher id, GMICE ICE
- o Critical Competent check using software in research field.

Present Position

- ➤ Assistant Professor (Ad-Hoc) at B R Harne College of Engineering and Technology under consolidated pay band of 41k per month (Feb 2021 till date).
- ➤ Research Scholar (Accomplished Jan 2015- August 2020), National Institute of Technology, Surat (SVNIT), on Improvement of Geometric design of roundabout for pedestrian crossing under Road Safety Audit, Transportation Engineering and pavement design Lab.

Education

> Ph. D. -Transportation, (January 2015 to August 2020)

Thesis entitled: "Improvement of Geometric design of roundabout for pedestrian crossing under Road Safety Audit" under the supervision of Dr. Rakesh Kumar, Dr. N J Mistry, Professor, SVNIT Surat, Gujarat, India.

Autonomous Institute: Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology-395007.

Marks Secured: 8.56 CGPA

> Master's Degree in Environmental Engineering (2012-2014) SVNIT Surat, Gujarat, India.

Marks Secured: 7.61 CGPA

➤ Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering -General (2008-2011) KDK College of Engineering, Nagpur, RTM Nagpur University.

Subjects: Civil Engineering, Environmental Engineering (Elective) and

Pavement Design (Elective) Percentage Secured: 68.5%.

> HSSC RTM Nagpur University, Pune Board (2007)

SFS College Nagpur

Subjects: General Science (PCMB)

Percentage Secured: 73.17%

> SSC, Central School, CBSE Board (2005)

Kendriya Vidyalaya Nagpur

Subjects: General Science (PCMB)

Percentage Secured: 56.6%

> National Conference Proceedings

Conference Publications

1. Apeksha Mendhe, Rakesh Kumar, N J Mistry. "Indian scenario: study of high-speed rail corridor". Proceedings dated 21-23, 2017, 4th international conference on Industrial Engineering (ICIE-2017). Vol (I), ISBN: 987-93-86238-39-9 (Book Proceedings Printed Article PUBLISHED- National - Presenting/ First Author).

- Apeksha Mendhe, Rakesh Kumar, N J Mistry. "Pedestrian Crossing at Roundabout using Central Composite Design Approach". Proceedings 2018, 6th World conference on Applied Science, Engineering and Technology (WCASET-IFERP-2018). ISBN: 978-81-932966-9-1 (Compendium Proceedings Print PUBLISHED - National - Presenting/ First Author).
- 3. Apeksha Mendhe, Rakesh Kumar, N J Mistry. "Risk Evaluation of Pedestrian Crossing at Indian Urban Roundabout". Proceedings 2018, 6th World conference on Applied Science, Engineering and Technology (WCASET-IFERP-2018). ISBN: 978-81-932966-9-1 (Compendium Proceedings Print PUBLISHED National Presenting/ First Author).

> International Conference Proceedings

- 1 Apeksha Mendhe, Sandeep Tamgadge and Nilesh Tambe. "Countryside Lawsuit for Pedestrian Safety A Literature under Road safety Audit". Second ASCE India Conference on "Challenges of Resilient and Sustainable Infrastructure Development in Emerging Economies" (CRSIDE2020), Hotel Novotel, Kolkata, March 2-4, 2020 (International Presenting/ First Author)
- 2 Apeksha Mendhe, Rakesh Kumar and N J Mistry." *Economic Evaluation for AHP Ranked Pedestrians crossing Retrofit Solutions Geometrical Improvement at Roundabout*". Second ASCE India Conference on "Challenges of Resilient and Sustainable Infrastructure Development in Emerging Economies" (CRSIDE2020), Hotel Novotel, Kolkata, March 2-4, 2020 (International Presenting/ First Author)
- 3 Apeksha Mendhe, Rakesh Kumar, N J Mistry. "Optimization of central island by SITI Equation inclusive of pedestrian facility on roundabout" (Article ID: 17), pp.745-756. Urbanization Challenges in emerging economics, ASCE Proceedings, [https://ascelibrary.org/doi/10.1061/9780784482025.076] (Sci-Proceedings Printed & Online Article PUBLISHED- International -Presenting/ First Author).
- 4 Apeksha Mendhe, N J Mistry, R A Christian. "Review of Pharmaceutical wastewater generation, impact assessment and wastewater treatment technology". Hydro International conference on Hydraulics, Water Resources and River Engineering, Uttarakhand, Organized by IIT-Roorkee, India 17-19 Dec 2015. (Online Proceedings, International Presenting/First Author)

> International Journal Article publications

- 1. Apeksha Adesh Mendhe, N J Mistry, Rakesh Kumar (April 2019). Analysis of Reduction in Pedestrian Waiting Time for Crossing Roundabout. (Article ID: IJCIET_10)04_072. *International Journal of Civil Engineering and Technology (IJCIET,2019)*. Vol. (10), issue 4, April 2019. ISSN Print: 0976-6308 and ISSN Online: 0976-6316, pp. 684-694. Impact factor:9.1, Scopus indexed, peer-reviewed journal (Scopus Article PUBLISHED).
- Apeksha Adesh Mendhe, Rakesh Kumar, N J Mistry (June 2018). Analysis of Multi Bump Barrier augmented zebra crossing for pedestrian at roundabout (Article ID: IJCIET_09)06_042. *International Journal of Civil Engineering and*

Journal Articles

Technology (IJCIET, 2018). Vol. (9), Issue 6, June 2018. ISSN Print: 0976-6308 and ISSN Online: 0976-6316, pp. 363-372. Impact factor: 9.1, Scopus indexed, peerreviewed journal (**Scopus Article PUBLISHED**).

3. Mendhe A A, Kumar, R, and Mistry N J (2012). Optimization of roundabout design elements Tehnicki Vjesnik-Technical Gazette journal doi:10.1061/9780784482025.076 (SCI-indexed Article PUBLISHED)

> National Journal Article publications

None

Books/Book Chapter Publication

None

Principal Subjects/

Civil Engineering, Environmental Engineering, Pavement design, Traffic and Transportation Engineering under Road Safety Audit.

Teaching Experience

T a4i44-a	Subject taught	Subject taught	Duration	Experience
Institutes	(BE)	(Mtech/ME)	Duration	Lapertence
B R Harne	-TRE-I	Research	Complete	15/06/2021- till
College of	-Water	Methodology	semester	date
Engineering,	Resources			
Vangani	Engineering-II			
Raigarh				
B R Harne	-TRE-II	Reliability	Complete	15/02/2021 -
College of	-Environmental	Engineering	Semester	15/06/2021
Engineering,	Management			
Vangani				
Raigarh				
G H Raisoni	-	No subject	3 months	3 months
College of		allotted/		
engineering		administrative		
and technology		work		
(GHRCEM),				
Wagholi Pune				

Early career Activity

Dynamic person since school days. Sportsperson; Handball regional player, silver medalist. Trekker (Camping) at Himachal Pradesh organized by National Adventure Foundation. Para-sailing, Rope Rappling, rivercrossing, rock climbing as extracurricular activities, 2 gradual years Woman cricketer at PG level collegiate tournament gold medalist.

Research History

> DOCTORAL STUDIES

- Institute- Svnit, Surat Gujarat, From Jan 2015 To August 2020
- **Position:** Worked as Full Time Institute Research Scholar (Ph.D.)
- **Topic:** Improvement of geometric design of roundabout or pedestrian crossing under Road Safety Audit.
- Review of characteristics of elderly road users at intersection and roundabout. Selection of alternatives over existing pedestrian crossing characteristics using analytical hierarchy process (AHP). Non-motorized traffic crossing at roundabouts using synchronized geometry improvement, practices adopted as mitigation measures. Onsite design of experiment (DOE) as work establishment of multiple bump barrier (MBB), analysis and results. Validation protocol model as central composite design using design expert software for MBB. Trial and error equation development methodology governing relation between central island diameter, circular weaving width with inscribed circle diameter (ICD).
- Institute- SVNIT, Surat, Gujarat from Jan 2015 To Aug 2020
- -Associated Teaching with Full Time Institute Research (FIR). Classes arrangements, deliver lectures, practical lab handling and management (qualities, quotations and billing), tutorials valuations, exam paper setter, exam invigilator duty, exam paper valuation.

> Professional Experience

- **Institute** National Environmental Engineering Research Institute (Neeri), Nagpur, Maharashtra from June 2014 Dec 2014
- -Project Assistant- Level I International Water Safety Plan by World Health Organization (WHO) for Developing country like India
- -Drinking water safety plan implementation in and around Nagpur and Amravati city accomplished Drinking water testing for various properties and water characteristics at frequent interval, report preparation etc.

> MTECH STUDIES

Institute- Svnit, Surat Gujarat from Jan 2012 – May 2014

- **M.Tech. Thesis:** Direct DO BOD relationship using Fuzzy modelling on Wastewater Effluent.
- Associated Lab Handling @ assistance-ship 6k/ month

Fellowship & Awards

1. PhD TEQIP-II (Technical Education Quality Improvement Program, Government of India), All India Council of technical Education, Full Time Institute Research Scholarship, Jan 2015 till 2020. 25K for 2015-2017 and 28K for 2017- 2019.

Certification

Certification course	Affiliation	Participated/ Successful/ grade	Year of participation
Certificate of	American	Successfully	2018
Associate Member	Society of Civil	elected	
in ASCE			

	Engineer		
	(ASCE)		
Conference Poster	American	Successfully	2017
Presentation	Society of Civil	presented and	
Certificate	Engineer	attended	
	(ASCE)		
Certificate of	Sardar	Successfully	2017
Statistics of	Vallabhbhai	attended	
Experimenters	National		
	Institute of		
	Technology		
State of Art	Sardar	Successfully	2016
practices for	Vallabhbhai	attended	
characterisation of	National		
pavement materials	Institute of		
and evaluation of	Technology		
pavements, two			
weeks (TEQIP-II)			
1 week Workshop	Visvesvaraya	Successfully	2016
on Data Mining	National	attended	
(DMR)	Institute of		
	Technology		
PTV Vissim	PTV Group	Successfully	2016
Training Course	•	attended	
Finishing school on	Sardar	Successfully	2014
Statistics of	Vallabhbhai	attended	
Experiments	National		
(TEQIP-II)	Institute of		
	Technology		
1-week STTP on	Sardar	Successfully	2013
Advances on	Vallabhbhai	participated	
wastewater	National		
treatment and	Institute of		
energy generation	Technology		
30 wpm	Maharashtra	A grade	2011
Typewriting	state council of		
	examinations,		
	Pune (Govt		
	commercial		
	certificate		
	examination)		

Selfassessment Language

Language(s) English, Hindi, Marathi

Understanding	Speaking	Writing
Yes	Yes	Yes

Technical Skills

- 1. Can Operate Design Expert Software
- **2.** Basics in AutoCAD draftsmanship.
- **3.** Analysis and Validation of work by technically sound research work (SPSS software) and research article writing

Computer Skills

- 1. Fluent in operating various software tools required for Transportation based studies & analysis. MS-Office, Turnitin software in research plagiarism.
- 2. Well-aware of high throughput on new technologies and software.

Reference Person

Dr. Anant Parghi (Post-Doc) Assistant Professor

Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Icchachanath Surat- 395007.

Email: anantparghi@gmail.com Phone: +91 9428457867,

+916352587181

Dr. Rakesh Kumar, PhD

Professor,

Transportation Engineering Dept. Civil Engineering Department Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Surat (Gujarat), India

Email: - <u>krakesh1999@gmail.com</u> Contact No.: - +919662039082.

Dr. Atul Pradeep Daiwile, PhD (Post-doc)

3120 Saint Paul Street, Apt No. A402, Baltimore, MD, 21218. Qtr. No. A/4, Gorewada Water Workers NMC Colony, Gorewada Road, Nagpur- 440013, Maharashtra, India

Email: atul.daiwile@nih.gov, daiwile@gmail.com

Phone: +919975214750,

+14109006398 / +917709225758

Dr. N J Mistry

Retd. Professor Environmental Engineering Dept. Civil Engineering Department Genova Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology Surat (Gujarat), India Tel:(+91) – 9426138288,

Email: <u>njm@ced.svnit.ac.in</u>

Dr. APEKSHA MENDHE

PhD, SVNIT, Surat Gujarat India -395007